Mss.B.B445
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Catalogs, 1939 December (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Two catalogs: "Barcroft-Warburg Apparatus & Glassware," and "Orthmann Laboratories, Inc."
  - Cattell, Jaques, 1944 June - 1945 March (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Cattell, Jaques
    Contains three letters concerning the reviewing by Max Bergmann for the journal "Science." The last letter in the correspondence is from Bergmann's secretary to Cattell informing him of Bergmann's death. Also included is a copy of Bergmann's review of "Optical Activity and Living Matter," by G.F. Gause, published in "Science" on June 30, 1944.
  - Cattell, James McKeen, 1936 September - 1944 May (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Cattell, James McKeen
    Letters concerning Max Bergmann's work on the review board of "Science," articles written by Bergmann, and personal correspondence.
  - Chargaff, Erwin, 1942 June - 1943 January (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Chargaff, Erwin
    Correspondence regarding different chemicals. Also, a questionnaire needed for Chargaff to be employed with the U.S. War Production Program.
  - Chemical Rubber Corp., 1941 April (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Chemical Rubber Corp.
    Orders placed for lab apparatus by Max Bergmann.
  - Chibnall, A. Charles, No. 1, 1938 February - December (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Chibnall, A. Charles, No. 1
    Letters concerning Chibnall's visits to the lab at the Rockefeller Institute in September and November 1938.
  - Chibnall, A. Charles, No. 2, 1943 February - December (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Chibnall, A. Charles
    Rough notes about Chibnall and his publications for his upcoming lecture at the Rockefeller Institute. Diagram's for Chibnall's talk.
  - Chibnall, A. Charles, No. 3, 1942 July (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Chibnall, A. Charles, No. 3
    Copy of Chibnall's "Bakerian Lecture" delivered July 16, 1942.
  - Chou, Chiyuan, No. 1, 1940 October - 1946 January (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Chou, Chiyuan, No. 1
    Personal and professional correspondence. Includes letters about Chou's initial visit to New York and his employment in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Chou, Chiyuan, No. 2, 1940 December - 1941 September (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Chou, Chiyuan, No. 2
    Personal correspondence to Max Bergmann and other lab members at the Rockefeller Institute including Christmas cards, and wedding announcements.
  - Chou, Edith J H, 1944 August - September (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Chou, Edith J. H.
    Correspondence regarding a voluteer position in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Christensen, Halvor N, 1944 October - November (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Christensen, Halvor N.
    Correspondence regarding a manuscript sent to Max Bergmann.
  - Ciereszko, Leon Stanley, 1942 February (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Ciereszko, Leon Stanley
    Correspondence regarding a job at Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Clark, W. Mansfield, 1942 July (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Clark, W. Mansfield
    Manuscript sent to Clark. Describes a method developed in Max Bergmann's lab on the measurement of solubility on a semi-micro scale.
  - Clarke, Hans Thatcher, No. 1, 1934 April - 1940 December (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Clarke, Hans Thatcher, No. 1
    General and personal correspondence. Includes: letters of thanks for reprints, letters of recommendation for Conrad Bloch by Max Bergmann to Clarke, also Heinrich Waelsch, Chiyuan Chou and Heinz Fraenkel-Conrat, and a recommendation by Clarke for Joseph Fruton to the American Society of Biological Chemists. Various invitations to dinners and meetings. Some analyses from Herman Fischer sent to Clarkes lab.
  - Clarke, Hans Thatcher, No. 2, 1941 January - 1944 August (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Clarke, Hans Thatcher, No. 2
    General Correspondence. Letter inviting Clarke to speak at the Rockefeller Institute. Several letters of recommendation written by Clarke and Max Bergmann. Inquiries from Bergmann to Clarke in regards to finding someone to work in his lab. A letter asking Bergmann to give comments on a recent manuscript written by Clarke to be published in the "Journal of Biological Chemistry."
  - Clowes, George H. A., 1938 December - 1939 February (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Clowes, George H. A.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and George H. A. Clowes (of the Lilly Research Laboratories). Letter of recommendation for a protein chemist from Bergmann to Clowes. Letter concerning a special type of insulin given by Lilly Co. to Bergmann for his research.
  - Cohen, Joseph H., 1938 January - February (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Cohen, Joseph H.
    Correspondence regarding the invitation of Max Bergmann to be a guest at the New Century Club of Boston.
  - Cohn, Alfred Einstein, 1934 March - 1941 October (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Cohn, Alfred Einstein
    General correspondence. A letter informing Cohn of his appointment to the "Rockefeller Institute Committee of the Staff Meetings."
  - Cohn, Edwin J., No. 1, 1941 February - April (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Cohn, Edwin J., No. 1
    Correspondence regarding protein samples.
  - Cohn, Edwin J., No. 2, 1937 March - 1940 January (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Cohn, Edwin J., No. 2
    General correspondence. Letters regarding chemicals. A request by Cohn to Bergmann for more information on Sidney W. Fox. Invitations to speak at Harvard and the Rockefeller Institute both to and from Max Bergmann. Letters describing the state of work in both Bergmann and Cohn's labs.
  - Columbia University, 1936 February - February 1942 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Columbia University
    A letter seeking information regarding University classes. Invitations to two lectures: November, 1939 and February, 1942.
  - Commercial Solvents Corporation., 1941 October - November (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Commercial Solvents Corporation
    Advertisements, requests for chemicals, and receipts of payment.
  - Committee on Carbohydrate Nomenclature, 1941 April (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Committee on Carbohydrate Nomenclature of the ACS
    Revised memorandum and the "Final Report" given to the Committee on Carbohydrate Nomenclature.
  - Connolly, Nora, 1939 November - 1943 July (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Connolly, Nora
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Nora Connolly. Includes a note of well wishes to Bergmann during his illness.
  - Corn Exchange Bank Trust Co., New York., 1942 January - 1944 May (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Corn Exchange Bank Trust Company
    Correspondence concerning accounts and statements.
  - Coutts & Company, 1942 February - 1944 January (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Coutts & Company
    Correspondence regarding Max Bergmann's subscription to "The Chemical Society of London."
  - Corxatto, H, 1942 January - 1944 December (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Corxatto, H
    Requests for chemicals from Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Cruz-Coke, E, 1941 April (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Cruz-Coke, E.
    Letter discussing kidney enzymes and dehydrogenated peptides.
  - Curme, George O, 1944 February - June (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Curme, George O.
    Congratulatory notes from Max Bergmann to Curme on his elction to the National Academy of Sciences and his recent award of a William Gibbs Medal.
  - Curtis Publishing Company, 1942 March - April (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Curtis Publishing Company
    Receipts of payment.
  - D - Misc., No. 1, 1937 August - 1945 October (Box 5, Folder 29)
    D - Misc., No. 1-5
    General materials from August 10, 1934- October 15, 1945. Approximately 200 pp.
  - D - Misc., No. 2, 1934 September - 1941 March (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - D - Misc., No. 3, 1940 November - 1944 July (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - D - Misc., No. 4, 1934 August - 1942 August (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - D - Misc., No. 5, 1936 June - 1944 April (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Da Fano, Ettore, 1940 May - 1941 January (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Da Fano, Ettore
    Correspondence between Da Fano and Max Bergmann concerning employment for Da Fano. Included are copies of Da Fano's curriculum vitae, resume, and a summary of his life.
  - Dakin, Henry D., No. 1, 1941 November - 1943 November (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Dakin, Henry D., No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Dakin.
  - Dakin, Henry D., No. 2, 1934 August - 1937 March (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Dakin, Henry D., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Henry Dakin.
  - Dakin, Henry D., No. 3, 1934 May - 1940 November (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Dakin, Henry D., No. 3
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Henry Dakin.
  - Dam, Henrik, 1945 October - 1946 February (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Daniel, Ruth Ortmann, 1936 July (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Daniel, Ruth Ortmann
    Curriculum vitae and references.
  - Degering, E. F., 1938 January - February (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Degering, E. F.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and E. F. Degering. Requests for Bergmann to tour the Mid-Western Co-operating sections of the American Chemical Society.
  - Demerec, Milislav, 1941 January - February (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Demerec, Milislav
    Request for Max Bergmann to take part in the Cold Spring Harbor Symposium in the summer of 1941.
  - Demonstrations, 1939 January - September (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Demonstrations
    List of outlines for demonstrations given by Bergmann at his lab.
  - Demuth, F., 1937 May - 1940 October (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Demuth, F.
    Correspondence concerning job placement for refugees. Includes several curriculum vitae and letters of recommendation.
  - Dictionary of Biochemistry, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Dictionary of Biochemistry
    Advertisements announcing the publication of the Dictionary of Biochemistry.
  - Doherty, David, 1941 February - 1945 November (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Doherty, David
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and David Doherty. Includes a letter of recommendation for Doherty to the Office of Naval Officer Procurement.
  - Donnan, Frederick George, 1934 June - 1937 January (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Donnan, Frederick George
    Correspondence concerning Max Bergmann's appointment to the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Drury, Betty, 1940 September - December (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Drury, Betty
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Betty Drury (Executive Secretary of the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars). Letters concern job placement for refugees.
  - Dubos, Rene Jules, 1944 February - June (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Dubos, Rene Jules
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Rene Dubos. Includes a congratulatory note from Bergmann to Dubos on his appointment as a member of the Rockefeller Institute. Other letters discuss the substance gramicidin.
  - Dunn, M. S., No. 1, 1941 May - October (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Dunn, M. S., No. 1
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Dunn regarding methods of isolating glycine, alanine, and serine. Includes a detailed description of the process written by Bergmann.
  - Dunn, M. S., No. 2, 1940 October - 1942 March (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Dunn, M. S., No. 2
    A letter of recommendation to Max Bergmann from Dunn regarding the nomination of Sidney Fox to the American Society of Biological Chemists. Other letters discuss Bergmann's work with phenylhydrazine and histidine.
  - Duschinsky, Robert, 1936 September - 1941 January (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Duschinsky, Robert
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Robert Duschinsky. Letters include notes of thanks for reprints, Duschinsky's application for a post at Bergmann's lab, and several letters discussing the plight of German refugees.
  - du Vigneaud, Vincent, No. 1, 1934 April - 1940 December (Box 6, Folder 18)
    du Vigneaud, Vincent, No. 1
    Recommendation to Max Bergmann of Dr. Loring and a list of Loring's publications. Information on chemicals and preparation of chemicals. Letters about filling positions at the Rockefeller Institute and George Washington University. Invitations to Bergmann for meetings.
  - du Vigneaud, Vincent, No. 2, 1941 May - 1944 June (Box 6, Folder 19)
    du Vigneaud, Vincent, No. 2
    Personal correspondence. Includes dinner invitations, letters about experiments, and the exchange of reprints.
  - E - Misc., No. 1, 1938 March - 1942 March (Box 6, Folder 20)
    E - Misc., No.1
    General miscellaneous material. Letter discussing plans for vacation and also a program for the ceremonial cornerstone laying of the Eastern Regional Research Laboratory in Wyndmoor, Pa., including a map and transit routes of the area.
  - E - Misc., No. 2, 1936 March - 1943 June (Box 6, Folder 21)
    E - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous material. Includes a letter of recommendation written by Bergmann, requests for reprints, and personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Robert Ehrmann.
  - E - Misc., No. 3, 1935 April - 1943 June (Box 6, Folder 22)
    E - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous materials. Includes request for reprints, letters of recommendation, and letters discussing experiments.
  - E - Misc., No. 4, 1936 September - 1942 February (Box 6, Folder 23)
    E - Misc., No. 4
    General miscellaneous material. Includes letters of recommendation for: Freidrich Phillip Ellinger (curriculum vitae included), Chi yuan-Chou, Gabriel Kitzinger, Heinz Fraenkel-Conrat. Other materials consist of invitations to dinner and requests for reprints.
  - E - Misc., No. 5, 1935 May - 1941 September (Box 6, Folder 24)
    E - Misc., No. 5
    General miscellaneous material. An invitation to speak at the Johns Hopkins University Research Conference. Also a recommendation written to the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Physicians on behalf of Heinz Fraenkl-Conrat.
  - Eastman Kodak Company, No. 1, 1937 September - 1939 November (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Eastman Kodak Company, No. 1
    Request for catalogs by Max Bergmann, reciepts of payment, requests for reprints, and letters of apology for delay of supplies.
  - Eastman Kodak Company, No. 2, 1941 January - October (Box 6, Folder 26)
    Eastman Kodak Company, No. 2
    Letters from Max Bergmann requesting chemicals, cameras, and information about articles printed by the Eastman Kodak Company.
  - Edlbacher, S., 1938 December - 1939 June (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Edlbacher, S.
    Correspondence regarding employment for Edlbacher.
  - Egloff, Gustav, 1943 October (Box 6, Folder 28)
    Egloff, Gustav
    A copy of an article titled "Germany Committs Scientific Suicide" sent to Max Bergmann for his comments.
  - Eimer & Amend, 1936 April - 1939 February (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Eimer & Amend
    Supply slips for apparatus and chemicals, orders, and general inquiries.
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Einstein, Albert
    A letter from Albert Einstein to Max Bergmann requesting the recommendation of a chemist for his lab.
  - Eisendrath, David B., 1934 December - 1939 September (Box 6, Folder 31)
    Eisendrath, David B.
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and David Eisendrath. Includes notes of well wishes, notes of thanks, and dinner invitations.
  - Eisenstein, Alfred, 1940 July - November (Box 6, Folder 32)
    Eisenstein, Alfred
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Alfred Eisenstein.
  - Elderfield, Robert C., 1936 December - 1940 December (Box 6, Folder 33)
    Elderfield, Robert C.
    Letters from Max Bergmann to Elderfield declining invitations to speak at conferences.
  - Ellern, Herbert, 1935 December (Box 6, Folder 34)
    Ellern, Herbert
    Curriculum vitae, resume, and photograph.
  - Elman, Robert, No. 1, 1939 February - 1940 July (Box 6, Folder 35)
    Elman, Robert, No. 1
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Robert Elman. Letters discuss technical problems of Elman's work and arrangements for visits to Bergmann's lab.
  - Elman, Robert, No. 2, 1940 December - 1943 March (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Elman, Robert, No. 2
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Robert Elman. Includes notes of thanks, Bergmann's comments on a paper written by Elman, and a discussion concerning the situation of Dr. Fritz Lieben (curriculum vitae included).
  - Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars, 1944 May - 1941 April (Box 6, Folder 37)
    Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars. Letters are in regards to the recommendation of refugees to and from Bergmann and the Committee. Includes recommendations for: Karl Schon (curriculum vitae included), Otto Schwartzkopff, Hans M. Cassel (curriculum vitae included), Dr. Moritz Kohn, and Ruth B. Neufield-Crzellitzer (curriculum vitae included).
  - Emery, Alden H., 1940 March - 1944 May (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Emery, Alden H.
    Letters concerning meetings of the American Chemical Society. Includes invitations for Max Bergmann to speak and do a lecture tour.
  - Engelhardt, W. A., 1942 March (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Engelhardt, W. A.
    Reprint of an article titled "Enzymatic and Mechanical Properties of Muscle Proteins."
  - F - Misc., No. 1, 1934 December - 1943 May (Box 7, Folder 3)
    F - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous files. Includes invitations to speaking engagements and letters of recommendation.
  - F - Misc., No. 2, 1936 February - 1944 September (Box 7, Folder 4)
    F - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous files. Includes correspondence regarding chemical samples, experiments, letters of recommendation, and invitations to speaking engagements.
  - F - Misc., No. 3, 1937 October - 1940 April (Box 7, Folder 5)
    F - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous files. Includes correspondence regarding the situation of Dr. Otto Meyerhoff in Heidelberg, Germany.
  - F - Misc., No. 4, 1938 January - 1941 December (Box 7, Folder 6)
    F - Misc., No. 4
    General miscellaneous files. Includes correspondence regarding chemicals, experiments, dinner invitations, and notes of thanks.
  - F - Misc., No. 5, 1935 September - 1944 November (Box 7, Folder 7)
    F - Misc., No. 5
    General miscellaneous files. Includes correspondence regarding invitations, requests for reprints, notes of thanks, and letters of recommendation. Letters pertaining to Bergmann's illness. A Western Union telegram from Joseph Fruton informing Heinz Fraenkel-Conrat of Bergmann's death. Correspondence between Bergmann and Walter Frankford discussing Bergmann's "iron tannage" process and also Bergmann's thoughts on the war in Europe.
  - Fairchild, David, 1936 March - 1944 September (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Fairchild, David
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and David Fairchild regarding experiments and methods.
  - Fajans, Kasimir, 1940 November - 1941 June (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Fajans, Kasimir
    Correspondence regarding the recommendation of possible students from Max Bergmann to Kasimir Fajans.
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1942 October - 1943 December (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Federal Bureau of Investigation
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and the Federal Bureau of Investigation concerning mail sent to Bergmann from Germany.
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, 1934 November (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology
    Circular to members and programs of meetings.
  - Feibelmann, Richard, 1941 January - 1943 May (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Feibelmann, Richard
    Letters of recommendation from Max Bergmann to Richard Feibelmann. Bergmann writes to Feibelmann on behalf of recently arrived German refugees.
  - Feigl, Fritz, 1942 May - 1944 November (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Feigl, Fritz
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Fritz Feigl. Feigl writes to Bergmann to discuss the position of Dr. Moritz Kohn. Letters discussin Feigl's son attending college in the United States.
  - Feuchtwanger, Marie-Louise, 1943 August - October (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Feuchtwanger, Marie-Louise
    Letters concerning employment in the United States.
  - Fingermann, Steffi, 1940 June - 1942 August (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Fingermann, Steffi
  - Fink, Robert M., 1940 November - 1941 March (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Fink, Robert M.
    Letters concerning the possibility of Fink working for one year in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Fire Extinguisher, 1941 November (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Fire Extinguisher
    Hand written and typed copies of a "Report on CO2 Extinguisher Demonstration."
  - Fischer, Emil (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Fischer, Hermann O. L., No. 1, 1940 April - 1941 June (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Fischer, Herman O. L., No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Herman Fischer. Letters concern various experiments, exchange of papers, and arrangements for lectures to be given by both Bergmann and Fischer. One letter discusses the efforts to free a Professor Friedrich Epstein out of a concentration camp in southern France.
  - Fischer, Hermann O. L., No. 2, 1937 November - 1940 January (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Fischer, Herman O. L., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Herman Fischer. Letters discussing the coming war in Europe and the implications it will have on the future. Letters regarding job prospects for German refugees and how to get a Professor Strauss out of Germany. Letters about Bergmann's efforts to get a paper of Mendel's and Fischer's published in "Science." Note of reprints sent to Fischer.
  - Flaschner, Erich, 1939 May - June (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Flaschner, Erich
    Letter to Max Bergmann from Erich Flaschner (leather chemist and German refugee residing in London) regarding job prospects in the United States. Includes a copy of Flaschner's curriculum vitae.
  - Flexner, Simon, 1935 April - 1940 December (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Flexner, Simon
    General progress report of the analysis of progestin. Letters of thanks for reprints from both Max Bergmann and Simon Flexner.
  - Flinn, Waldo R., No. 1, 1941 May - 1945 June (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Flinn, Waldo R., No. 1
    Letters showing the forwarding of job applications. Notes on the vacation policy of the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Flinn, Waldo R., No. 2, 1936 February - 1943 February (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Flinn, Waldo R., No. 2
    Administrative information and policies of the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Foa, Piero, 1939 March - June (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Foa, Piero
    Letters concerning employment. Includes copies of both Dr. Piero Foa's and his father Dr. Carlos Foa's curriculum vitae.
  - Fordham University, 1942 Janaury - 1944 February (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Fordham University
  - Fox, Sidney W., No. 1, 1944 November - 1941 October (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Fox, Sidney W., No. 1
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Sidney Fox. Congratulatory notes to Fox on the birth of his son and on becoming an assistant professor at the University of Iowa. Requests for reprints.
  - Fox, Sidney W., No. 2, 1935 August - 1940 April (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Fox, Sidney W., No. 2
    Letters from Fox informing Max Bergmann of his progress, jobs, and whereabouts.
  - Fraenkel-Conrat, Heinz, No. 1, 1941 August - 1944 November (Box 7, Folder 29)
    Fraenkel-Conrat, Heinz
    Summary of an experiment sent by Fraenkel-Conrat to the Journal of the American Chemical Society. Letters asking for Max Bergmann's advice over preparation of chemical compounds. Notes of thanks to Bergmann for job recommendations and his assistance in Fraenkel-Conrat recieving his naturalization papers. Letters to Bergmann informing him of Fraenkel-Conrat's job changes.
  - Fraenkel-Conrat, Heinz, No. 2, 1933 August - 1940 December (Box 7, Folder 30)
    Fraenkel-Conrat, Heinz, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Heinz Fraenkel-Conrat. Letters regarding the naturalization of Fraenkel-Conrat. Letters concerning employment. Letters of recommendation. Copy of Fraenkel-Conrat's curriculum vitae.
  - Freudenberg, Walter, 1934 May - June (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Freudenberg, Walter
    Discussion of a method to treat leather with salt resulting in "salzstippen" leather.
  - Freundlich, Herbert, 1939 February (Box 7, Folder 32)